{
    "id": "410f78c13f8049b6a3c16428b17aa17f",
    "title": "Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. a call from him in the morning.",
            "description": "The past simple is more common with expressions like in the morning. ",
            "answers": [
                "received",
                "have received",
                "had received"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me what ……………………",
            "description": "The past perfect is more appropriate to talk about the earlier of two past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "happened",
                "had happened",
                "has happened"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I ……………………… an attorney.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will become",
                "would become",
                "would have become"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I heard them ………………………. in the other room.",
            "description": "Either the gerund or the infinitive without to is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "talking",
                "talk",
                "to talk"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. the truth.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Speak",
                "Talk",
                "Tell"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you ……………………… another job.",
            "description": "The simple past is used after would rather. ",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "found",
                "have found"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is high time he ……………………. smoking.",
            "description": "The past simple is used after it is high time. ",
            "answers": [
                "quits",
                "quit",
                "will quit"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When I met him yesterday I ……………………… him about my problems.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have told",
                "had told",
                "told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He was acquitted ………………………. the charges levelled against him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "from",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We reached the theatre after the movie ………………………..",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "began",
                "had begun",
                "has begun"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for him but he ………………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't came",
                "didn't come",
                "hadn't come"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You haven’t returned the vacuum cleaner you …………………….. from me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have borrowed",
                "borrowed",
                "borrow"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}